O. H. Robertson Papers 1918-1966 Mss.B.R546
American Philosophical Society
O. H. (Oswald Hope) Robertson Papers
1917-1969
Mss.B.R546
American Philosophical Society
7.0 Linear feet Ca. 4,500 items
A physician and naturalist, Oswald Hope Robertson worked at the Rockefeller Institute, the Peking Union Medical College, and at the medical school of University of Chicago (1927-1951). With a broad range of research interests, Robertson contributed important work on the transmission of pneumonia, the disinfection of air with glycol vapors, and later in his career, on the physiology and ecology of salmonid fishes. He is best remembered, however, as the creator of the first blood bank, established for use by British and American forces during the First World War. The Robertson Papers contain correspondence, notes, articles, and notebooks on many of Robertson's major research interests, including his work on blood. His early work on salmonid ecology is represented in a journal and eleven notebooks stemming from fieldwork in the lakes of the Wind River Range in northwestern Wyoming, 1942-1951. There is also interesting material on the Research Corporation (New York City) concerning patents on glycol vapors and air sterilizers, as well as notes and manuscripts of papers on morphine experiments, canine pneumococcus, bacteremia, and the effects of hydrocortisone.
Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
Bibliography
Bibliographic references to works cited in the finding aid, implicitly or explicitly.
Related Archival Materials note
The APS also houses the papers of Peyton Rous and several of Robertson's peers at the Rockefeller Institute, including James B. Murphy, Eugene Opie, Leon Cole, and Harold Amoss.
The Rockefeller Archive Center houses additional papers of Oswald Robertson.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Ruth Robertson, 1970 (accession number 1970-1312ms).
Scope and Contents note
The Robertson Papers contain correspondence, notes, articles, and notebooks, relating to Oswald Hope Robertson's diverse research interests, including his work on blood. In particular, the collection contains important information on Robertson's research on the cold storage of blood and blood banking, including both clinical notes on transfusion using preserved blood and animal research at the front during the First World War.
Aware of the commercial potential of his research, Robertson was involved with the Research Corporation (New York City) in securing patents on glycol vapors and air sterilizers, and with the same agency, kept notes and manuscripts on his morphine experiments, canine pneumococcus, Bacteremia, and the effects of hydrocortisone.
Finally, Robertson's interest in ecology is reflected in a journal and nine volumes of notebooks containing data collected in 1942 to 1944 while conducting a study of the trout and vegetation of lakes in the Wind River Range of northwestern Wyoming.
Biographical/Historical note
The pathologist who established the first blood banks, Oswald Hope Robertson was born in Woolwich, England in 1886, and moved to the San Joaquin Valley, California, at the age of two. Following completion of his BS and MS at the University of California, Robertson entered Harvard for his medical degree (1913), and remained in Boston as an intern at Massachusetts General Hospital. From his days as a graduate student, he took an active research interest in haematology, winning a Dalton post-graduate Scholarship to study pernicious anemia, and working under Roger I. Lee on transfusion and clotting. Blood would remain with him throughout his career.
In 1915, Robertson was recruited to the Rockefeller Institute to work under the direction of Peyton Rous. His career at the Rockefeller was to be brief, however. With America's entry into the war in Europe, he enlisted with a medical team from Massachusetts General Hospital to serve with the American and British Expeditionary Forces in France. There, he and J. R. Turner put their knowledge of blood cell survival to use, introducing a citrate and glucose solution that extended the life of blood for several days by preventing clotting and providing nourishment to the cells, respectively. With Rous's input, Robertson and Turner recognized the potential to establish a series of "blood depots," forerunners to the modern blood bank, in which preserved blood was collected from O-positive (universal) donors to store for use in emergency deployment, without the need for verifying blood type of the donee. For his efforts, Robertson, still a British citizen, was awarded the Distinguished Service Order of Great Britain in 1919.
Although Robertson returned to the Rockefeller briefly after the completion of his military obligations, in 1919 he accepted an associate professorship at the newly established Peking Union Medical College in Beijing, China, later becoming Full Professor (1923-1927) and head of the department. Still hoping to pursue his interest in anemia, medical necessity again called, as he turned to the study of pneumonia and pulmonary infections.
Robertson's work on pneumonia and pulmonary diseases gathered steam after he returned to the United States in 1927. Accepting a position as head of the Department of Medicine at the University of Chicago, Robertson explored the use of glycol vapors as a means of preventing the spread of airborne infection. As it had in 1917, his research brought him to the attention of the military, and with the outbreak of Second World War, earned him a position as the civilian Director of the Commission on Air-Borne Infections (1941-1950). Along with Rous, he was also instrumental in establishing the first civilian blood bank in the United States at the Cook County Hospital. He remained at Chicago until retiring to emeritus status in 1951.
From the 1930s onward, Robertson was increasingly absorbed in projects only distantly related to his medical research. Having begun college intending on a career in biology, and following a holiday to the Wind River Mountains in Wyoming, Robertson indulged his interests in the ecology and physiology of the salmonid fishes. After his retirement from Chicago, he moved to California and took up research on fishes full time, culminating in an important experimental investigation of the salmonid endocrine system, based on the trout and salmon native to the area around Santa Cruz where he had settled.
He died in Santa Cruz on March 23, 1966, leaving his wife, Ruth, and three children.
Bayne-Jones, Stanhope, 1888-1970; Blake, Francis Gilman, 1887-1952; Castle, William B., (William Bosworth), 1897-; Cole, Rufus Ivory, 1872-1966; Graeser, James B.; Loosli, Clayton G., 1905-1976; Minot, George Richards, 1885-1950; Mudd, Stuart, 1893-; Noguchi, Hideyo, 1876-1928; Park, Edwards A., (Edwards Albert), 1877-1967; Peking Union Medical College; Puck, Theodore T., (Theodore Thomas), 1916-2005; Research Corporation; Rockefeller University.; Rous, Peyton, 1879-1970; Smillie, Wilson George, 1886-1971; University of Chicago.; Van Slyke, Donald Dexter, 1883-1971; Articles; Bacteremia.; Biology; Blood banks -- France -- 1914-1918.; Disinfection and disinfectants.; Dogs--Diseases; Ecology.; Fishes; Hydrocortisone; Lakes--Wyoming; Medical sciences; Medicine--Research; Morphine; Notebooks; Notes; Pathology; Pneumonia; Salmonidae--Research; Wind River Range (Wyo.); World War, 1914-1918
- Series I. Correspondence, 1918-1966; 3 linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Professional correspondence.
  - Adams, Robert M (Box 1)
  - Addis, Thomas (Box 1)
  - AirBurification Service, Inc. (Box 1)
  - Air Research Associates (Box 1)
  - Allee, W Clyde (Box 1)
  - Allen, Archer (Box 1)
  - Allison, Leonard N (Box 1)
  - Allison, V D (Box 1)
  - Alpert, Mrs. Lucille P (Box 1)
  - Alsever, John (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 1)
  - American Association of North China (Box 1)
  - American Association of Textile Chemists and colorists (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors (Box 1)
  - American Consular Service Tientsin, China (Box 1)
  - American Fisheries Society (Box 1)
  - American Library Service (Box 1)
  - American Medical Association (Box 1)
  - American Pediatric Society (Box 1)
  - American Philosophical Society (Box 1)
  - American Public Health Assoc. (Box 1)
  - American Public Health Assoc. Committee on Air Sanitation (Box 1)
  - American Society for clinical Investigation (Box 1)
  - American Society for Experimental Pathology (Box 1)
  - Anderson Galleries (Box 1)
  - Annand, Donald (Box 1)
  - Appel, Elizabeth (Box 1)
  - Applegate, Vernon C (Box 1)
  - Armour Company (Box 1)
  - Arnold, Lloyd (Box 1)
  - Association of American Physicians (Box 1)
    General note
    8.27.75
  - Atkinson, Clinton E (Box 1)
  - Atwater, John (Box 1)
  - Atz, James W (Box 1)
  - Auer, Otis N, to Charles R Phillips (Box 1)
  - Avery, O T (Box 1)
  - Bachmeyer, Arthur C (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Edward W (Box 1)
  - Baker, Burton L (Box 1)
  - Baker, John E (Box 1)
  - Baker, M D, to Henry Wise (Box 1)
  - Barker, Joseph W (Box 1)
  - Barnett, Alfred H (Box 1)
  - Bauer, Walter (Box 1)
  - Bayne-Jones, S (Box 1)
  - Bazzicalupo, C (Box 1)
  - Beck, Ralph V (Box 1)
  - Beeson, Edward I (Box 1)
  - Belding, David L (Box 1)
  - Belt, Elmer (Box 1)
  - Bernoys, Edward L (Box 1)
  - Bernstein, Clarence (Box 1)
  - Bigg, Edward (Box 1)
  - Binger, Carl (Box 1)
  - Blake, Francis G (Box 1)
  - Blalock, Alfred (Box 1)
  - Bock, Arlie (Box 1)
  - Bodansky, Meyer (Box 1)
  - Bolin, Rolf L (Box 1)
  - Bonner, John (Box 1)
  - Boobjerg, Dick (Box 1)
  - Bourdillon, R B (Box 1)
  - Brayshaw, T (Box 1)
  - Breasted, Charles (Box 1)
  - Breasted, James H (Box 1)
  - Brennemann, Joseph (Box 1)
  - Briggs, John C (Box 1)
  - Brinkley, Mary (Box 1)
  - British Ecological Society (Box 1)
  - Brithish Medical Journal (Box 1)
  - Brophy, William A (Box 1)
  - Brown, C J D (Box 1)
  - Brown, E W (Box 1)
  - Brown, John W (Box 1)
  - Brues, Austin M (Box 1)
  - Brunschwig, Alexander (Box 1)
  - Bryson, Vernon (Box 1)
  - Buchbinder, Leon (Box 1)
  - Bull, Carroll G (Box 1)
  - Bullowa, Jesse G M (Box 1)
  - Burroughs, A L (Box 1)
  - Burrows, Roger E (Box 1)
  - Burwell, C Sidney (Box 1)
  - California Academy of Medicine (Box 2)
  - California Board of Medical Examiners (Box 2)
  - California Department of Employment (Box 2)
  - California. Dept. of Fish and Game (Box 2)
  - California State Automobile Association (Box 2)
  - Camm, Oliver (Box 2)
  - Canada Army -Dept. of National Defence (Box 2)
  - Canada - Fisheries Research Bd. (Box 2)
  - Cannon, Walter B (Box 2)
  - Capps, Joseph A (Box 2)
  - Cardinelli, Frank (Box 2)
  - Carlisle, J M (Box 2)
  - Castaneda, M Ruiz (Box 2)
  - Castle, William B (Box 2)
  - Cecil, Russell L (Box 2)
  - Cerophyl Laboratories, Inc. (Box 2)
  - Challinor, S W (Box 2)
  - Chamerlin, Rollin (Box 2)
  - Chaney, Albert L Chaney Chemical Laboratory (Box 2)
  - Chapman, Edward N (Box 2)
  - Cheer, S N (Box 2)
  - Chicago Society of Internal Mecicine (Box 2)
  - Child, C M (Box 2)
  - Chitty, Dennis (Box 2)
  - Christian, Jack (Box 2)
  - Christian Medical Council for Overseas Work (Box 2)
  - Clark, David B (Box 2)
  - Clarke, George L, to Thomas Park (Box 2)
  - Clarke, Hans T (Box 2)
  - Cloverland Electric CoOperative (Box 2)
  - Clute, Howard M (Box 2)
  - Coburn, Alvin F (Box 2)
  - Coggleshall, Lowell T (Box 2)
  - Cohn, Alfred E (Box 2)
  - Cole, Rufus (Box 2)
  - Collier, John (Box 2)
  - Compton, Frederick L (Box 2)
  - Cook. Thomas Cook and Son (Box 2)
  - Cooper, Gerald P (Box 2)
  - Cope, O B (Box 2)
  - Cortlett. R.J. Cortlett & Sons (Box 2)
  - Coutts (Box 2)
  - Cowden, Ambrose (Box 2)
  - Cowdry, E V (Box 2)
  - Cramer, Frederic (Box 2)
  - Creaser, C W (Box 2)
  - Cruikshank, Robert (Box 2)
  - Curtis, Bryan (Box 2)
  - Daily, W A (Box 2)
  - Dale, Henry (Box 2)
  - Davidson, F A (Box 2)
  - Davis, David E (Box 2)
  - De Gowin, Elmer L (Box 2)
  - Detwiler, S R (Box 2)
  - Dieuaide, Francis R (Box 2)
  - Doan, Charles A (Box 2)
  - Dochez, A R (Box 2)
  - Donaldson, Lauren R (Box 2)
  - Donaldson, Lauren R (Box 2)
  - Dooner, Hugh P (Box 2)
  - Douglas, Paul H (Box 2)
  - Draper, George W (Box 2)
  - Duff-Stevens, Calvin J (Box 2)
  - Dunklin, Edward (Box 2)
  - DuShane, Graham (Box 2)
  - Ecologists Union (Box 2)
  - Edwards, H S (Box 2)
  - Eichelberger, Lillian (Box 2)
  - Elbert, B F (Box 2)
  - Emerson, Alfred (Box 2)
  - Errington, Paul L (Box 2)
  - Faust, Clarence (Box 2)
  - Favour, Cutting B (Box 2)
  - Fenjohn Underwater Photo & Equipment Co. (Box 2)
  - Fleischmann, Walter (Box 2)
  - Flexner, Simon (Box 2)
  - Flook, Lyman R (Box 2)
  - Foss, Mrs. Julian (Box 2)
  - Fox, John P (Box 2)
  - Franck, James (Box 2)
  - Fraser, John (Box 2)
  - Gay, Frederick Parker (Box 2)
  - Geiling, E M K (Box 2)
  - General Electric Company (Box 2)
  - Gilmore, Hugh R (Box 2)
  - Goetz, Alexander (Box 2)
  - Gonzalez, Jose Oliver (Box 2)
  - Gorgas. William Crawford (Box 2)
  - Graeser, James B (Box 2)
  - Greeley, John R (Box 2)
  - Greene (Box 2)
  - Greene, Charles W (Box 2)
  - Gregg, Lucien A (Box 2)
  - Greiner Glass Blowing Co. (Box 2)
  - Grimson, Keith S (Box 2)
  - Gutman, Alexander (Box 2)
  - Hadler, Arthur J (Box 2)
  - Hallock, Richard J (Box 2)
  - Halver, John E (Box 2)
  - Hamburger, Morton Jr. (Box 2)
  - Hamburger, Walter W (Box 2)
  - Hamilton, Bengt (Box 2)
  - Hanson, Joseph O (Box 2)
  - Hardin, Robert C (Box 2)
  - Hardisly, Irving (Box 2)
  - Hardy, David P (Box 2)
  - Hare, Ronald (Box 2)
  - Hargett, M V (Box 2)
  - Harris, Hayden B (Box 2)
  - Harrison, R W (Box 2)
  - Harrower, James K (Box 2)
  - Harvard Medical School Dommitory Fund (Box 2)
  - Harvey Society (Lecture) (Box 2)
  - Hasler, A D (Box 2)
  - Hastings, A Baird (Box 2)
  - Haviland, James W (Box 2)
  - Hazzard, Albert H (Box 2)
  - Heffron, Roderick (Box 3)
  - Heidelberger, Michael (Box 3)
  - Herrera, Julio Roberto (Box 3)
  - Hoagland, Hudson (Box 3)
  - Hoar, William S (Box 3)
  - Hoffmann-La Roche, Inc. (Box 3)
  - Hollaender, Alexander (Box 3)
  - Holmes, Harlan B (Box 3)
  - Holt, L Emmett (Box 3)
  - Hoover, Theodore (Box 3)
  - Horsman, C E (Box 3)
  - Houck, George H (Box 3)
  - Houghten, F C (Box 3)
  - Houghton, H S (Box 3)
  - Howard, John E (Box 3)
  - Hubbs, Carl L (Box 3)
  - Hudson, N Paul (Box 3)
  - Huggins, Charles (Box 3)
  - Humphreys, Eleanor (Box 3)
  - Hunt, Reid (Box 3)
  - Hunter, Floyd (Box 3)
  - Hunter, William S (Box 3)
  - Hurd, Richmond (Box 3)
  - Hutchins, Louis W (Box 3)
  - Hutchins, Robert M (Box 3)
  - Idaho, Dept. of Fish & Game (Box 3)
  - Ingle, Dwight S (Box 3)
  - Institute of Medicine of Chicago (Box 3)
  - International Biochemical Corp. (Box 3)
  - Irons, Ernest E (Box 3)
  - Irvin, D (Box 3)
  - Irvin, J M (Box 3)
  - Irvin, Nora (Box 3)
  - James, Charles A (Box 3)
  - Johannsen, O A (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Harlan E (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Warren C (Box 3)
  - Jones, Mrs. Clayton (Box 3)
  - Juday, Chancey, to Thomas Park (Box 3)
  - Kahn, Reuben L (Box 3)
  - Kaiser, Albert (Box 3)
  - Karsher, Howard T (Box 3)
  - Kaye, Saul (Box 3)
  - Kerr, Andrew L (Box 3)
  - Kerr, William J (Box 3)
  - Kessel, J F (Box 3)
  - Kilgore, Alson (Box 3)
  - Koch, Fred Conrad (Box 3)
  - Korns, Robert F (Box 3)
  - Kudo, R R (Box 3)
  - Kym, Otto (Box 3)
  - Lai, Daniel (Box 3)
  - Lairds' Lodge (Box 3)
  - Landsteiner, Karl (Box 3)
  - Langmuir, Alexander P (Box 3)
  - Larsen, Lis Olesen (Box 3)
  - Larson, M Burneice (Box 3)
  - LaRue, George R (Box 3)
  - Lawrence, John S (Box 3)
  - Leavens, Dickson H (Box 3)
  - Lederle Laboratories (Box 3)
  - Lee, C V (Box 3)
  - Lee, Roger I (Box 3)
  - Leiter, Louis (Box 3)
  - Lemon, Henry M (Box 3)
  - Leonard, J W (Box 3)
  - Leopold, A C (Box 3)
  - Lester, William (Box 3)
  - Levy, Mordechai (Box 3)
  - Eli Lilly and Co. (Box 3)
  - Lim, Robert K S (Box 3)
  - Limbach, Bruno von (Box 3)
  - Lindberg, H A (Box 3)
  - Liu, Shao-Kwang (Box 3)
  - Lloyd Library (Box 3)
  - Long, Esmond (Box 3)
  - Longcope, Warfield T (Box 3)
  - Loosli, Clayton G (Box 3)
  - Los Angeles Academy of Medicine (Box 3)
  - Loucks, Harold (Box 3)
  - Luckhardt, Arno B (Box 3)
  - Lundeberg, Karl R (Box 3)
  - Luzac and Company (Box 3)
  - McDermand, Charles M (Box 3)
  - McFarland, Ross A (Box 3)
  - McIntyre, Ross T (Box 3)
  - Macklin, C C (Box 3)
  - McLean, Franklin C (Box 3)
  - McNamara, William E (Box 3)
  - MacNee, J W (Box 3)
  - Magee, James C (Box 3)
  - Maina, B A (Box 3)
  - Majors, E W (Box 3)
  - Marine, David (Box 3)
  - Matthews, Samuel A (Box 3)
  - Meakins, J C (Box 3)
  - Means, J Howard (Box 3)
  - Meehean, O Lloyd (Box 3)
  - Meleney, Frank (Box 3)
  - Meleney, Henry E (Box 3)
  - Melton, H R (Box 3)
  - Merck Institute for Therapeutic Research (Box 3)
  - Merriman, Daniel (Box 3)
  - Meyer, K F (Box 3)
  - Michigan Dept. of Conservation, Scientific Fishing Permit (Box 3)
  - Michigan Dept. of State (Box 3)
  - Miller, Benjamin F (Box 3)
  - Miller, Mal (Box 3)
  - Mindt, George R (Box 3)
  - Minot, George B (Box 3)
  - Moffett, James W (Box 3)
  - Monge, Charles (Box 3)
  - Montano, Julio (Box 3)
  - Moore, Carl R (Box 3)
  - Morgan, Hugh J (Box 3)
  - Morrell, George (Box 3)
  - Moulton, F R (Box 3)
  - Mudd, Stuart (Box 3)
  - National Academy of Sciences (Box 4)
  - National Georgraphic Society (Box 4)
  - National Research Council (Box 4)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 4)
  - Neal, Paul (Box 4)
  - Needham, Paul R (Box 4)
  - New Hampshire Fish & Game Department (Box 4)
  - New York City Dept. of Health, Bureau of Laboratories (Box 4)
  - Newcombe, Curtis L, to Thomas Park (Box 4)
  - Nicolle, Charles (Box 4)
  - Nobel Committee (Box 4)
  - Noguchi, Hiedyo (Box 4)
  - Normile, Hubert C (Box 4)
  - O'Brien, R A (Box 4)
  - O'Brien, Theo W (Box 4)
  - O'Connor, R B (Box 4)
  - Ogle, Dan C (Box 4)
  - Opie, Eugene (Box 4)
  - Overbeeke, A P van (Box 4)
  - A. Paladini, Inc. (Box 4)
  - Park, Edwards A (Box 4)
  - Park, Thomas (Box 4)
  - Parke, Davis & Company (Box 4)
  - Passano Foundation (Box 4)
  - Passports (Box 4)
  - Peabody, Francis W (Box 4)
  - Pearce, Richard M (Box 4)
  - Peking (China) Union Medical College (Box 4)
  - Pelnar, John (Box 4)
  - Pennak, Robert W, to Thomas Park (Box 4)
  - Pepper, O H Perry (Box 4)
  - Pettijohn, Francis J (Box 4)
  - Pickford, Grance E (Box 4)
  - Pierrotti, Joseph (Box 4)
  - Pitelka, Frank A (Box 4)
  - Ella Sachs Plotz Foundation (Box 4)
  - Pomeroy, B S (Box 4)
  - Poole, F E (Box 4)
  - Precision Scientific Company (Box 4)
  - Prescott, Thomas (Box 4)
  - Prigal, Samuel J (Box 4)
  - Puck, Theodore (Box 4)
  - The Quadrange Club (Box 4)
  - Rackemann, Farncis M (Box 4)
  - Raulston, B O (Box 4)
  - Redfern William W (Box 4)
  - Reimann, Hobart A (Box 4)
  - Reineke, E P (Box 4)
  - Reprint Requests (Box 4)
  - Research Corporation (Box 4)
  - Retirement Dinner Testimonials (Box 5)
    - Bachmeyer, A C (Box 5)
    - Barron, E S Guzman (Box 5)
    - Graeser, Henry (Box 5)
    - Hutchins, Robert M (Box 5)
    - Johnson, Victor (Box 5)
    - Loosli, Clayton (Box 5)
    - Palmer, Walter (Box 5)
    - Park, Ted (Box 5)
    - Rous, Peyton (Box 5)
    - Wise, Henry (Box 5)
  - Reynolds, Dexter B (Box 5)
  - Reynolds, Thomas E (Box 5)
  - Rich, Mrs. Marguerite (Box 5)
  - Rich, Willis H (Box 5)
  - Richards, Lois W (Box 5)
  - Richards, Rosalind (Box 5)
  - Ricker, W E (Box 5)
  - Rivers, Thomas M (Box 5)
  - Roberts, A M (Box 5)
  - Robertson, A White (Box 5)
  - Robertson, Casper (Box 5)
  - Robertson, Mrs. Kathleen (Box 5)
  - Robertson, Mrs. Nellie (Box 5)
  - Robertson, Russell C (Box 5)
  - Robertson, Theodore. (Box 5)
    - Marriage Certificate (Box 5)
  - Rochester Academy of Medicine (Box 5)
  - Rockefeller Institute (Box 5)
  - Roelofs, Eugene (Box 5)
  - Rous, Mrs. Marion (Box 5)
  - Rous, Peyton, 1917-1969 (Box 5)
  - Rous, Peyton to Ruth Robertson (Box 5)
  - Rous, Peyton: Biographical notes (Box 5)
  - Rous, Peyton: re Kober Medal to Robertson (Box 5)
  - Rowley, D (Box 5)
  - Rountree, Leonard G (Box 5)
  - Salter, William T (Box 5)
  - Save-the-Redwoods League (Box 5)
  - Sawyer, Wilbur A (Box 5)
  - Schmitt, Waldo, to Thomas Park (Box 5)
  - Schwentker, Francis F (Box 5)
  - Science (Box 5)
  - The Science Press (Box 5)
  - Scott, John W (Box 5)
  - Scully, James A (Box 5)
  - G. D. Searle and Company (Box 5)
  - Sellards, Watson (Box 5)
  - Sendroy, Julius, Jr. (Box 5)
  - Severinghaus, Aura E (Box 5)
  - Shannon, H A (Box 5)
  - Shattock, George C (Box 5)
  - Shepardson, R B (Box 5)
  - Shetter, David S (Box 5)
  - Shields, Randolph (Box 5)
  - Shope, Richard E (Box 5)
  - Shust, Stanley (Box 5)
  - Sifton, Praed & Co. (Box 5)
  - Simmons, James Stevens (Box 5)
  - Simon, James R (Box 5)
  - Slater, Daniel W (Box 5)
  - Smillie, Wilson G (Box 5)
  - Smith, Charles (Box 6)
  - Smith, H W (Box 6)
  - Smith, Margaret H D (Box 6)
  - Smith, Phillips S (Box 6)
  - Smith, Stuart B (Box 6)
  - Smyly, H J (Box 6)
  - Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine (Box 6)
  - The Society of Sigma Xi (Box 6)
  - Solman, Victor E F (Box 6)
  - Sonkin, Larry (Box 6)
  - Speers, James F (Box 6)
  - Spies, Tom D (Box 6)
  - Spink, Wesley W (Box 6)
  - E. R. Squibb & Sons (Box 6)
  - Stagnaro, Malio J (Box 6)
  - Stanford Universtiy (Box 6)
  - Stanley, W M (Box 6)
  - Stauffer, Thomas (Box 6)
  - Stephenson, Charles S (Box 6)
  - Stern, Curt (Box 6)
  - Stillman, Ernest (Box 6)
  - Stokes, Joseph, Jr. (Box 6)
  - Stone, William S (Box 6)
  - Storer, Tracy I (Box 6)
  - Strode, George K (Box 6)
  - Strong, Edward K Jr. (Box 6)
  - Strong, Richmond W (Box 6)
  - Sturgis, Cyrus R (Box 6)
  - Surber, Thaddeus (Box 6)
  - Sutliff, Wheelan D (Box 6)
  - Sweet, Clifford (Box 6)
  - Swift, Harold (Box 6)
  - Swift, Homer F (Box 6)
  - Szego, Clara (Box 6)
  - Taft, Alan C (Box 6)
  - Taliaferro, W H (Box 6)
  - Tarzwell, Clarence M (Box 6)
  - Taylor, C V (Box 6)
  - Ten Broeck, Carl (Box 6)
  - Terrell, Edward E (Box 6)
  - Thomas, Sydney F (Box 6)
  - Thompson, David H (Box 6)
  - Todd, Gordon B (Box 6)
  - Twitty, Victor C (Box 6)
  - Uhlenhuth, Edward C (Box 6)
  - Uhley, Charles G (Box 6)
  - Union Carbide and Carbon Corp. (Box 6)
  - United States Army (Box 6)
  - United States Department of Agrigultur (Box 6)
  - United States Coast & Geodetic Survey Department of Commerce (Box 6)
  - United States National Bureau of Standards (Box 6)
  - United States Dept. of Interior-Fish & Wildlife Service (Box 6)
  - U.S. Treasury Department. Internal Revenue Service: Narcotics (Box 6)
  - U.S. Merchant Marine-Cadet Basic School (Box 6)
  - U.S. War Dept. Office of Surgeon General (Box 6)
  - University of California (Box 6)
  - University of California Medical School Grade Report, 1910-11 (Box 6)
  - University of California Real Estate Office (Box 6)
  - University of Chicago Department of Medicine (Box 6)
  - University of Chicago: Ecology Club (Box 6)
  - Unknowns (Box 6)
  - Upjohn Company (Box 6)
  - Van Slyke, Donald D (Box 6)
  - Vander Starr, Charles (Box 6)
  - Vestal, E H (Box 6)
  - Vincent, George E (Box 6)
  - Vladykov, Vadim D (Box 6)
  - Waksman, Selman A (Box 6)
  - Walford, Lionel A (Box 6)
  - Walford, Roy L (Box 6)
  - Walker, Arthur M (Box 6)
  - Walker, Eugene (Box 6)
  - Waring, James J (Box 6)
  - Watson, C J (Box 6)
  - Watson, Percy T (Box 6)
  - Webb, G C (Box 6)
  - Webster, Leslie T (Box 6)
  - Weiss, Paul (Box 6)
  - Weiss, Soma (Box 6)
  - Welch, Paul S (Box 6)
  - Wells, Mildred Weeks (Box 6)
  - Wells, William F (Box 6)
  - Whitaker, Douglas M (Box 6)
  - Whitby, Lionel E H (Box 6)
  - White, H C (Box 6)
  - Wigglesworth, George (Box 6)
  - Willner, Otto (Box 6)
  - Winternitz, M C (Box 6)
  - Wise, Henry (Box 6)
  - Wolf, Louis E (Box 6)
  - Woo, G T (Box 6)
  - Wood, L (Box 6)
  - Wood, W Barry, Jr. (Box 6)
  - Woodcock, J W (Box 6)
  - Woodhead, A D (Box 6)